manilatimes.net 2019-11-13

# Privacy Policy – The Manila Times

This site, www.manilatimes.net , is established and managed by The Manila Times, Publishing Company (“Manila Times”).

Manila Times respects your right to privacy in accordance to Republic Act No. 10173 or the Data Privacy Act of 2012. We shall only collect, record, hold, store, disclose, transfer, and use personal information as stated below. We will only keep your information for as long as we are either required to by law, ` relevant to the purposes for which it was collected.

By using this website, agree to the terms of this privacy policy. By accessing the Sites or utilizing the Services, you hereby consent to the use of your information, including your personal information, in the manner described in this Policy.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

Manila Times collects both personal information and non-personal information such as computer data.

When you visit Manila Times, our company servers will automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. This data may include:

Your computer’s IP address

  * Browser type
  * Device type
  * Domain names
  * The webpage you were visiting before you came to our Platform
  * The pages within the Platform which you visit
  * The time spent on those pages, items and information searched for on the Platform, access times and dates, and other statistics.

This information is collected for analysis and evaluation to help us improve the Platform and the Services we provide.

Web beacons are small graphic images that may be included on our Service and the Platform. They allow us to count users who have viewed these pages so that we can better understand your preference and interests.

We sometimes collect personally identifiable information, which may include:

  * Email address
  * Name
  * Birthday
  * Address
  * Mobile number
  * Landline number

We also at times collect anonymous demographic information such as the following:

  * Age
  * Gender
  * Location
  * Browsing behavior
  * Interests
  * Favorites

 **HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

Generally, we use personal information to analyze trends, administer the website, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for general use.

We also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from us, our affiliates, and partners.

When we hold surveys or promos, we may require users to give their contact information (such as name, email, or residential address or mobile number) and demographic information (such as age, income level, or gender).

This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest or to inform them if they have won in a certain contest or promo. We offer various email services. We require information from the user in order for him or her to avail of such free services. This information is used only as contact information and reference.

We partner with other parties to provide services that allow us to deliver the services under the website or assist us in measuring key website statistics.

When the user signs up for our services, we may be required to share names, or other information that is absolutely necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. In all cases, they are required to keep the information confidential.

Manila Times does not engage in the business of selling customers’ personal information to third parties.

 **USE OF COOKIES**

We use cookies to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. You are free to accept or decline cookies by modifying your browser setting to decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the features of the website.

Some of our business partners use cookies on our website. For the complete list and the key terms and conditions specifically applicable to each of our partners, please refer to the list in this link.

FindShare

<https://www.findshare.com/>

Cormant Technologies, Inc.

<http://www.cormanttech.com/>

Crowdynews

<https://www.crowdynews.com/>

 **HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Manila Times ensures that all information collected will be safe and secure. We shall protect all information you provided by:

  * Restricting access to personal information
  * Maintaining technology products to prevent unauthorized computer access
  * Securely destroying your personal information when it is no longer needed for any legal or business purposes

While we take these reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal information, no system or transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

If you believe that your privacy has been breached, contact us at our email address: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

You have the right to ask for a copy of any personal information we hold about you, as well as to ask for it to be corrected if you think it is wrong. To do so, please contact [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of every website that collects personally identifiable information.

 **CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Manila Times reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this policy shall be published on the Platform. By accessing and continuing to use this site, you confirm that you have read, understood, and agreed to this Privacy Policy and any subsequently modified Privacy Policy in its entirety.

 **MANILA TIMES’ RIGHT**

You acknowledge and agree that Manila Times has the right to disclose your personal information to any legal, regulatory, governmental, tax, law enforcement or other authorities or the relevant right owners, if Manila Times has reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure of your personal information is necessary for the purpose of meeting any obligations, requirements or arrangements, whether voluntary or mandatory, as a result of cooperating with an order, an investigation and/or a request of any nature by such parties. To the extent permissible by applicable law, you agree not to take any action and/or waive your rights to take any action against Manila Times for the disclosure of your personal information in these circumstances.

 **CONTACT US**

Should you have any concerns, queries, or comments, feel free to contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
